,title,clean_url,summary,uuid,neg,neu,pos,compound,spacy_entities
0,Ana Navarro Says Illegal Migrants Need To Be ‘Resettled Elsewhere',dailycaller.com,"'The View' co-host Ana Navarro called for illegal migrants to be moved from major U.S. cities and 'resettled elsewhere' Friday.
 
Navarro argued the U.S. is big enough to spread illegal migrants out and allow them to resettle outside of the overwhelmed big cities, despite suburbs and other rural areas having less funds or resources than major cities to provide for the migrants. Border officials have 
encountered
 over 1.9 million migrants at the U.S.-Mexico border in the 2023 fiscal year, prompting Republican Texas Gov.",fa68ea16830c2cc8b3d985dbafb27d53,0.107,0.859,0.034,-0.8225,"[{'ent_text': 'The View', 'ent_type': 'WORK_OF_ART'}, {'ent_text': 'Ana Navarro', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'U.S.', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Navarro', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'U.S.', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': '1.9 million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'U.S.-Mexico', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the 2023 fiscal year', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Republican', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Texas', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
1,Illegal Senegalese migrants among thousands released in Tucson,dailymail.co.uk,"By

Migrants from Senegal are among the thousands being released to the streets of Southwest border towns as federal processing centers are overcapacity as a crush of crossings cripples the nation. Street releases of migrants are being ordered in Tucson, Arizona, with migrants from African nations of Senegal, Mauritania, Ghana, Sudan part of the migrants who have recently made crossings into the US from Mexico. Those released are now forced to fend for themselves in intense heat and limited resources.",7e7755289f5e940dd27a302f539fc031,0.078,0.907,0.016,-0.6369,"[{'ent_text': 'Senegal', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Southwest', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Tucson', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Arizona', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'African', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Senegal', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Mauritania', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ghana', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sudan', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'US', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Mexico', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
2,EXCLUSIVE PHOTOS: 300 Migrants Stroll Across Biden Admin's ‘Closed' Border into Arizona on Labor Day,breitbart.com,"LUKEVILLE, Arizona — A single group of nearly 300 migrants walked through gates in the border wall welded open by the Biden administration west of Lukeville on Labor Day morning. The migrants eventually surrendered to Border Patrol agents at a nearby rally point. Breitbart Texas posted along the border in the small town and observed as Border Patrol agents prepared the migrants for transport to a Border Patrol processing center.

The large group consisted of migrants from a host of different countries including Venezuela, Nicaragua, the Peoples Republic of China, and the Islamic Republic of Mauritania.",e43c0591ce65896c0f2eeb34538db5b2,0.0,0.98,0.02,0.2263,"[{'ent_text': 'LUKEVILLE', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Arizona', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'nearly 300', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Biden', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Lukeville', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Labor Day morning', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Border Patrol', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Breitbart Texas', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Border Patrol', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Border Patrol', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Nicaragua', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the Peoples Republic of China', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the Islamic Republic of Mauritania', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
3,Tiny Italian island coping with thousands of migrants who arrived in a short span,breitbart.com,"A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa is overwhelmed as it copes with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week


Tiny Italian island coping with thousands of migrants who arrived in a short spanThe Associated PressMILAN






MILAN (AP) — A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.",86c1ae233098d27344d57a682f591f05,0.0,0.973,0.027,0.1027,"[{'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'PressMILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'MILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'AP', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
4,Tiny Italian island coping with thousands of migrants who arrived in a short span,independent.co.uk,"A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.
The 
Red Cross
 said 4,200 migrants remained at the center of the 6,800 who had swamped the tiny tourist and fishing island in a flotilla of some 120 boats arriving from 
Tunisia
. Transfers to the mainland were ongoing.
'After a particularly challenging day like yesterday, today people are being continuously transferred,'' said Francesca Basile of the 
Italian
 Red Cross.",9461b77fb30ec500361664c447d17645,0.0,0.941,0.059,0.5936,"[{'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '4,200', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '6,800', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'some 120', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'a particularly challenging', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'yesterday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'today', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Francesca Basile', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'the \nItalian\n Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
5,Tiny Italian island coping with thousands of migrants who arrived in a short span,ctvnews.ca,"MILAN -

A migrant reception centre in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.

The Red Cross said 4,200 migrants remained at the centre of the 6,800 who had swamped the tiny tourist and fishing island in a flotilla of some 120 boats arriving from Tunisia. Transfers to the mainland were ongoing.

""After a particularly challenging day like yesterday, today people are being continuously transferred,"" said Francesca Basile of the Italian Red Cross.",4ca6a0a4e2f4e0a31d7ba52b46fe5e94,0.0,0.941,0.059,0.5936,"[{'ent_text': 'MILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '4,200', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '6,800', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'some 120', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'a particularly challenging day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'yesterday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'today', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Francesca Basile', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
6,Exclusive Photos: Migrants from Around the World Stream Across 'Closed' Border into Arizona,breitbart.com,"LUKEVILLE, Arizona — More than 300 migrants walked through open storm drain gates in the border wall just west of Lukeville to surrender to Tucson Sector Border Patrol agents early Tuesday morning. Breitbart Texas watched as the migrants queued at the border wall before walking through the Organ Pipe National Monument Reserve, hoping to gain release into the United States. The group included migrants from several African nations, India, Pakistan, Ecuador, and Peru.


Of the more than 300 migrants making the trek through the desert reserve, few could speak Spanish or English.",7789ec4fc05f365a192e7237a24355c4,0.0,0.908,0.092,0.8402,"[{'ent_text': 'LUKEVILLE', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Arizona', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'More than 300', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Lukeville', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Tucson Sector Border Patrol', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'early Tuesday', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'morning', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'Breitbart', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Texas', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the Organ Pipe National Monument Reserve', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'the United States', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'African', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'India', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Pakistan', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ecuador', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Peru', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than 300', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Spanish', 'ent_type': 'LANGUAGE'}, {'ent_text': 'English', 'ent_type': 'LANGUAGE'}]"
7,Tiny Italian island coping with thousands of migrants who arrived in a short span,newsday.com,"MILAN — A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.

The Red Cross said 4,200 migrants remained at the center of the 6,800 who had swamped the tiny tourist and fishing island in a flotilla of some 120 boats arriving from Tunisia. Transfers to the mainland were ongoing.

'After a particularly challenging day like yesterday, today people are being continuously transferred,'' said Francesca Basile of the Italian Red Cross.",ba3a542e3969033fcb852bf46af4e637,0.0,0.941,0.059,0.5936,"[{'ent_text': 'MILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '4,200', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '6,800', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'some 120', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'a particularly challenging day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'yesterday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'today', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Francesca Basile', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
8,EXCLUSIVE VIDEO: 300 Mostly West African Migrants Cross Border into Arizona,breitbart.com,"LUKEVILLE, Arizona — In what Border Patrol agents describe as a daily event, more than 300 mostly West African migrants walked through drainage gates in the border wall several miles west of Lukeville, Arizona. The group contained around forty migrants from Peru, India, Ecuador, and several Middle Eastern countries, according to Border Patrol agents who spoke to Breitbart Texas.


The video. filmed on Tuesday in the Organ Pipe Monument National Reserve, shows the migrants staging along the border fence just after daybreak.",fffb2aceb1c8543d40507e3e721b5ca2,0.0,1.0,0.0,0.0,"[{'ent_text': 'LUKEVILLE', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Arizona', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Border Patrol', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'daily', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than 300', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'West African', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'several miles', 'ent_type': 'QUANTITY'}, {'ent_text': 'Lukeville', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Arizona', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'forty', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Peru', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'India', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ecuador', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Middle Eastern', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Border Patrol', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Breitbart Texas', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Tuesday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'the Organ Pipe Monument National Reserve', 'ent_type': 'FAC'}, {'ent_text': 'daybreak', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}]"
9,Tiny Italian island coping with thousands of migrants who arrived in a short span,apnews.com,"MILAN (AP) — A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.
The Red Cross said 4,200 migrants remained at the center of the 6,800 who had swamped the tiny tourist and fishing island in a flotilla of some 120 boats arriving from Tunisia. Transfers to the mainland were ongoing.
'After a particularly challenging day like yesterday, today people are being continuously transferred,'' said Francesca Basile of the Italian Red Cross.",cc2284e78c72dc5b4d7a58c1e59686cc,0.0,0.942,0.058,0.5936,"[{'ent_text': 'MILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '4,200', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '6,800', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'some 120', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'a particularly challenging day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'yesterday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'today', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Francesca Basile', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
10,Tiny Italian Island Coping with Thousands of Migrants Who Arrived in a Short Span,newsmax.com,"MILAN (AP) — A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.

The Red Cross said 4,200 migrants remained at the center of the 6,800 who had swamped the tiny tourist and fishing island in a flotilla of some 120 boats arriving from Tunisia. Transfers to the mainland were ongoing.

'After a particularly challenging day like yesterday, today people are being continuously transferred,'' said Francesca Basile of the Italian Red Cross.",422bd84c4ed478616c60342ea7ce95a6,0.0,0.942,0.058,0.5936,"[{'ent_text': 'MILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '4,200', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '6,800', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'some 120', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'a particularly challenging day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'yesterday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'today', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Francesca Basile', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
11,Exclusive Photos: Migrants from Around the World Stream Across ‘Closed' Border into Arizona,breitbart.com,"LUKEVILLE, Arizona — More than 300 migrants walked through open storm drain gates in the border wall just west of Lukeville to surrender to Tucson Sector Border Patrol agents early Tuesday morning. Breitbart Texas watched as the migrants queued at the border wall before walking through the Organ Pipe National Monument Reserve, hoping to gain release into the United States. The group included migrants from several African nations, India, Pakistan, Ecuador, and Peru.

Of the more than 300 migrants making the trek through the desert reserve, few could speak Spanish or English.",3164b3c02a5f608b06476c32883d0263,0.0,0.908,0.092,0.8402,"[{'ent_text': 'LUKEVILLE', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Arizona', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'More than 300', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Lukeville', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Tucson Sector Border Patrol', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'early Tuesday', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'morning', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'Breitbart', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Texas', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the Organ Pipe National Monument Reserve', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'the United States', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'African', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'India', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Pakistan', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ecuador', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Peru', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than 300', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Spanish', 'ent_type': 'LANGUAGE'}, {'ent_text': 'English', 'ent_type': 'LANGUAGE'}]"
12,EXCLUSIVE PHOTOS: 300 Migrants Stroll Across Biden Admin's 'Closed' Border into Arizona on Labor Day,breitbart.com,"LUKEVILLE, Arizona — A single group of nearly 300 migrants walked through gates in the border wall welded open by the Biden administration west of Lukeville on Labor Day morning. The migrants eventually surrendered to Border Patrol agents at a nearby rally point. Breitbart Texas posted along the border in the small town and observed as Border Patrol agents prepared the migrants for transport to a Border Patrol processing center.


A sign warns of the dangers of encountering human smugglers and migrants crossing from Mexico and marching through the desert.",0a0b69b2e5a68f60ed9345e2ab12e36e,0.074,0.906,0.02,-0.6249,"[{'ent_text': 'LUKEVILLE', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Arizona', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'nearly 300', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Biden', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Lukeville', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Labor Day morning', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Border Patrol', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Breitbart Texas', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Border Patrol', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Border Patrol', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Mexico', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
13,Tiny Italian island coping with thousands of migrants who arrived in a short span,yahoo.com,"MILAN (AP) — A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.
The Red Cross said 4,200 migrants remained at the center of the 6,800 who had swamped the tiny tourist and fishing island in a flotilla of some 120 boats arriving from Tunisia. Transfers to the mainland were ongoing.
'After a particularly challenging day like yesterday, today people are being continuously transferred,'' said Francesca Basile of the Italian Red Cross.",cb7caa4011a7fa32e02730969a2bb1d9,0.0,0.942,0.058,0.5936,"[{'ent_text': 'MILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '4,200', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '6,800', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'some 120', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'a particularly challenging day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'yesterday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'today', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Francesca Basile', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
14,Tiny Italian island copes with thousands of migrants who arrived in 24-hour span,latimes.com,"MILAN, Italy —

A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.

The Red Cross said 4,200 migrants remained at the center out of the 6,800 who had swamped the tiny tourist and fishing island in a flotilla of some 120 boats arriving from Tunisia. Transfers to the mainland were ongoing.

'After a particularly challenging day like yesterday, today people are being continuously transferred,'' said Francesca Basile of the Italian Red Cross.",cc75a1100948a84ccfe5cb5deb993355,0.0,0.943,0.057,0.5936,"[{'ent_text': 'MILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '4,200', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '6,800', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'some 120', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'a particularly challenging', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'yesterday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'today', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Francesca Basile', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'the Italian', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
15,Tiny Italian Island Coping With Thousands of Migrants Who Arrived in a Short Span,usnews.com,"MILAN (AP) — A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.

The Red Cross said 4,200 migrants remained at the center of the 6,800 who had swamped the tiny tourist and fishing island in a flotilla of some 120 boats arriving from Tunisia. Transfers to the mainland were ongoing.

'After a particularly challenging day like yesterday, today people are being continuously transferred,'' said Francesca Basile of the Italian Red Cross.",3d1563ee2b79e74a792c479f3c914afb,0.0,0.942,0.058,0.5936,"[{'ent_text': 'MILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '4,200', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '6,800', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'some 120', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'a particularly challenging day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'yesterday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'today', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Francesca Basile', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
16,Tiny Italian island coping with thousands of migrants who arrived in a short span,kdvr.com,"MILAN (AP) — A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.

The Red Cross said 4,200 migrants remained at the center of the 6,800 who had swamped the tiny tourist and fishing island in a flotilla of some 120 boats arriving from Tunisia. Transfers to the mainland were ongoing.

'After a particularly challenging day like yesterday, today people are being continuously transferred,'' said Francesca Basile of the Italian Red Cross.",14844d9b767d030b2b35fe5ea19cabe1,0.0,0.942,0.058,0.5936,"[{'ent_text': 'MILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '4,200', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '6,800', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'some 120', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'a particularly challenging day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'yesterday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'today', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Francesca Basile', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
17,Tiny Italian island coping with thousands of migrants who arrived in a short span,clickondetroit.com,"A woman and a child sleep outside the Lampedusa's migrant reception center, Sicily, early Thursday Sept. 14, 2023. The reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa remained critical Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week. (AP Photo/Valeria Ferraro)

MILAN – A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.",1d770886ae9343a26f5f6bfef169904d,0.024,0.963,0.013,-0.2732,"[{'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'early Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sept. 14, 2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Valeria Ferraro', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'MILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
18,Tiny Italian island coping with thousands of migrants who arrived in a short span,ktla.com,"MILAN (AP) — A migrant reception center in Italy's southernmost island of Lampedusa was overwhelmed Thursday as it coped with transferring to the mainland thousands of migrants who arrived on small, unseaworthy boats in a 24-hour span this week.

The Red Cross said 4,200 migrants remained at the center of the 6,800 who had swamped the tiny tourist and fishing island in a flotilla of some 120 boats arriving from Tunisia. Transfers to the mainland were ongoing.

'After a particularly challenging day like yesterday, today people are being continuously transferred,'' said Francesca Basile of the Italian Red Cross.",d92cdff890f63cbf8d12edffd3981787,0.0,0.942,0.058,0.5936,"[{'ent_text': 'MILAN', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '24-hour', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '4,200', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '6,800', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'some 120', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'a particularly challenging day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'yesterday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'today', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Francesca Basile', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Red Cross', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
19,500 Migrants in 4 Groups Apprehended in One Texas Border Sector over Labor Day Weekend,breitbart.com,"Over Labor Day Weekend, Del Rio Sector Border Patrol agents apprehended four large migrant groups who crossed the border from Mexico into Texas. The four groups totaled more than 500 migrants, an official reported.

Del Rio Sector Acting Chief Patrol Agent Juan G. Bernal posted a series of photos on Sunday showing four large migrant groups taken into custody by Eagle Pass Station agents.

Bernal reported the total number of migrants in the four groups came to 504 migrants.

'Our agents remain vigilant and determined to safeguard our nation's borders to ensure the safety of our communities,' Bernal wrote.",296dc00f0d888c4ea7553ce5743cf7e2,0.0,0.872,0.128,0.8932,"[{'ent_text': 'Labor Day Weekend', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Del Rio Sector', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'four', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mexico', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Texas', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'four', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'more than 500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Del Rio Sector', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Juan G. Bernal', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Sunday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'four', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Eagle Pass Station', 'ent_type': 'FAC'}, {'ent_text': 'Bernal', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'four', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '504', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Bernal', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}]"
