,title,clean_url,summary,published_date,uuid,neg,neu,pos,compound,spacy_entities
0,"We must protect refugees and allow them to flourish, say charities",thetablet.co.uk,"Jesuit Refugee Service and Caritas Westminster will be using the World Day of Migrants and Refugees in England and Wales on Sunday 24 September as an opportunity advocate for the rights of refugees and for policies that protect refugees and allow them to flourish.

Both charities are offering parish resources to mark the day including a text for speaking about the day at Mass, information for parish newsletters, ideas for bidding prayers and suggestions of what can be done as a parish community. A poster and a bookmark with the special prayer for the World Day of Prayer for Migrants and Refugees are also available.",2023-09-12 15:15:00,8f61f8c80e33399a779b19fbacc7866a,0.0,0.883,0.117,0.9042,"[{'ent_text': 'Jesuit Refugee Service', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Caritas Westminster', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the World Day of Migrants and Refugees', 'ent_type': 'EVENT'}, {'ent_text': 'England', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Wales', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sunday 24 September', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'the day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'the day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'the World Day of Prayer for Migrants and Refugees', 'ent_type': 'EVENT'}]"
1,Over 4 million Venezuelan migrants struggle for basic needs across the Americas,la-croix.com,"More than four million 
refugees and migrants from Venezuela
 still have trouble getting access to food, shelter, health care, education, and formal employment in Latin America and the Caribbean, despite attempts by host nations to legalize and integrate them.


According to the most recent Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (
RMNA
) for 2023, many Venezuelan migrants and refugees in the region lack reliable sources of income, making it challenging for them to successfully integrate into and contribute to host communities.",2023-09-13 22:00:00,ed6b19c1961e7b3d9fd3294e211c5383,0.056,0.854,0.09,0.4588,"[{'ent_text': 'More than four million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis', 'ent_type': 'LAW'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}]"
2,Over 4 Million Venezuelan refugees and migrants struggle to meet ...,unhcr.org,"GENEVA/PANAMA CITY – Despite efforts by host countries to regularize and integrate refugees and migrants from Venezuela, more than 4 million people still face difficulties accessing food, shelter, health care, education and formal employment in Latin America and the Caribbean.

The latest Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (RMNA) for 2023 shows that many Venezuelan refugees and migrants in the region lack stable livelihood opportunities, making it difficult for them to effectively integrate and contribute to host communities.",2023-09-12 12:53:59,183ab0ed387a90a5ab7f2def294c4d2d,0.079,0.778,0.143,0.6908,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than 4 million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis', 'ent_type': 'LAW'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}]"
3,Over Four Million Venezuelan Refugees and Migrants Struggle to Meet Basic Needs across the Americas,iom.int,"Over Four Million Venezuelan Refugees and Migrants Struggle to Meet Basic Needs across the Americas

Refugees and migrants from Venezuela enter one of the shelters the Brazilian government has installed in Pacaraima, with the support of international organizations, to offer them protection. Photo: R4V/Valmik Mota.

Geneva/Panama City – Despite efforts by host countries to regularize and integrate refugees and migrants from Venezuela, more than four million people still face difficulties accessing food, shelter, health care, education and formal employment in Latin America and the Caribbean.",2023-09-12 15:00:00,a69df36660a6986488f3b5e7f57555b8,0.049,0.886,0.065,0.34,"[{'ent_text': 'Over Four Million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Americas', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Brazilian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Pacaraima', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Valmik Mota', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Geneva', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Panama City', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than four million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}]"
4,Over Four Million Venezuelan Refugees and Migrants Struggle to Meet Basic Needs,modernghana.com,"Geneva/Panama City – Despite efforts by host countries to regularize and integrate refugees and migrants from Venezuela, more than four million people still face difficulties accessing food, shelter, health care, education and formal employment in Latin America and the Caribbean.

The latest Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (RMNA) for 2023 shows that many Venezuelan refugees and migrants in the region lack stable livelihood opportunities, making it difficult for them to effectively integrate and contribute to host communities.",2023-09-13 09:56:00,2e814b207898319fce0ab94ab18ad583,0.079,0.778,0.143,0.6908,"[{'ent_text': 'Geneva', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than four million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis', 'ent_type': 'LAW'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}]"
5,Over Four Million Venezuelan Refugees and Migrants Unable to Meet Basic Needs,newsghana.com.gh,"Tuesday 12 September 2023 I VIEW IN BROWSER
Over Four Million Venezuelan Refugees and Migrants Struggle to Meet Basic Needs Refugees and migrants from Venezuela enter a shelter installed by the Brazilian government in Pacaraima, with the support of international organizations, to offer them protection. Photo: R4V/Valmik Mota. 
 
Despite efforts by host countries to regularize and integrate refugees and migrants from Venezuela, more than four million people still face difficulties accessing food, shelter, health care, education and formal employment in Latin America and the Caribbean.",2023-09-12 00:00:00,0e74c0401cc2396ffe08806c4a9ba067,0.049,0.886,0.065,0.34,"[{'ent_text': 'Tuesday 12 September 2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Over Four Million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Brazilian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Pacaraima', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Valmik Mota', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than four million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}]"
6,Venezuelan Refugees And Migrants Struggle To Meet Basic Needs Across The Americas,menafn.com,"(MENAFN- Caribbean News Global)

SWITZERLAND / MEXICO, (IOM) – Despite efforts by host countries to regularize and integrate refugees and migrants from Venezuela, more than four million people still face difficulties accessing food, shelter, health care, education and formal employment in Latin America and the Caribbean.

The latest Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (RMNA) for 2023 shows that many Venezuelan refugees and migrants in the region lack stable livelihood opportunities, making it difficult for them to effectively integrate and contribute to host communities.",2023-09-13 00:00:00,56419f945fe42de462033549f9645c25,0.074,0.792,0.134,0.6908,"[{'ent_text': 'SWITZERLAND', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'MEXICO', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than four million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}]"
7,Over 4 Million Venezuelan refugees still face difficulties accessing basic needs,devdiscourse.com,"Despite efforts by host countries to regularize and integrate refugees and migrants from Venezuela, more than 4 million people still face difficulties accessing food, shelter, health care, education and formal employment in Latin America and the Caribbean.
 
The latest Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (RMNA) for 2023 shows that many Venezuelan refugees and migrants in the region lack stable livelihood opportunities, making it difficult for them to effectively integrate and contribute to host communities.",2023-09-13 06:26:38,4e7de8dd749b68fdca8c95c9306b5694,0.082,0.77,0.148,0.6908,"[{'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than 4 million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis', 'ent_type': 'LAW'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}]"
8,Over Four Million Venezuelan Refugees and Migrants Struggle to Meet Basic Needs across the Americas,reliefweb.int,"Geneva/Panama City – Despite efforts by host countries to regularize and integrate refugees and migrants from , more than four million people still face difficulties accessing food, shelter, health care, education and formal employment in Latin America and the Caribbean.


The latest 
Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (RMNA)
 for 2023 shows that many n refugees and migrants in the region lack stable livelihood opportunities, making it difficult for them to effectively integrate and contribute to host communities.",2023-09-14 08:59:15,0ddf1600be63b6312ba6a863c5c513b4,0.079,0.778,0.143,0.6908,"[{'ent_text': 'Geneva', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than four million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis', 'ent_type': 'LAW'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
9,"Bishops in Zimbabwe Call for Openness to Help ahead of World Day for Migrants, Refugees",aciafrica.org,"'Every migrant and refugee is unique and has a story to tell, and if that story is given a synodal listening ear, it can change the perceptions on how people look at the issue of migrants and refugees or those on the move,' they say.
 
In their statement, ZCBC members express their recognition of the rights of people on the move, saying they 'acknowledge that migrants and refugees should feel at home among us and that they are free to choose whether to migrate or to stay.'
 
'Migrants and refugees are humans with the same dignity as those who host them.",2023-09-15 08:25:00,2998f1ca672c5b567922b1a693d8a356,0.0,0.943,0.057,0.7184,"[{'ent_text': 'ZCBC', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
10,Venezuelan refugees and migrants struggle to meet basic needs across the Americas,caribbeannewsglobal.com,"SWITZERLAND / MEXICO, (IOM)
 – Despite efforts by host countries to regularize and integrate refugees and migrants from Venezuela, more than four million people still face difficulties accessing food, shelter, health care, education and formal employment in Latin America and the Caribbean.


The latest Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (RMNA) for 2023 shows that many Venezuelan refugees and migrants in the region lack stable livelihood opportunities, making it difficult for them to effectively integrate and contribute to host communities.",2023-09-13 01:22:42,403bc8da89e01175ff8afd490259800f,0.077,0.783,0.14,0.6908,"[{'ent_text': 'SWITZERLAND', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'MEXICO', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than four million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis', 'ent_type': 'LAW'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}]"
11,PANAMA MIGRANT CRISIS,naver.com,"More than 4 million Venezuelan migrants and refugees in Latin America need helpZachary Tomas (L) and Philippe Sacher, coordinators of the platform for Venezuelan migrants R4V, take part in the launch event of the Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (RMNA) for 2023, in Panama City, Panama, 12 September 2023. The United Nations warned that of the 6.5 million Venezuelan refugees and migrants hosted in 17 countries in Latin America and the Caribbean, more than four million have difficulties meeting the basic needs of food, medical services, education or housing.",2023-09-13 01:14:00,73b99875349f368aabc4589614c15263,0.046,0.924,0.03,-0.128,"[{'ent_text': 'More than 4 million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'helpZachary Tomas', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Philippe Sacher', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Panama City', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Panama', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': '12 September 2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'The United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '6.5 million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': '17', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'more than four million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}]"
12,Colombia: RMNA 2023: Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (issued September 2023),reliefweb.int,"Countries: Argentina, Aruba (The Netherlands), Bolivia (Plurinational State of), Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Costa Rica, Curaçao (The Netherlands), Dominican Republic, Ecuador, Guyana, Mexico, Panama, Paraguay, Peru, Trinidad and Tobago, Uruguay, (Bolivarian Republic of)


Source: R4V




Please refer to the attached files.


Description


The Regional Inter-Agency Coordination Platform for Refugees and Migrants from (R4V) issues this Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (RMNA) for 2023 to provide insights into the situation and varied challenges that refugees and migrants – both in-destination and in-transit – as well as their affected host communities face.",2023-09-12 12:24:20,4abc62c8785077117a35dfa7944e6aef,0.017,0.921,0.062,0.4767,"[{'ent_text': 'Argentina', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Aruba', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Netherlands', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Bolivia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Brazil', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Chile', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Colombia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Costa Rica', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Curaçao', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Netherlands', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Dominican Republic', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ecuador', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Guyana', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Mexico', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Panama', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Paraguay', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Peru', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Trinidad and Tobago', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Uruguay', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Bolivarian Republic of', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'R4V', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'The Regional Inter-Agency Coordination Platform for Refugees and Migrants from', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
13,100 Afghan refugees return home from Iran,thefrontierpost.com,"KABUL (Khaama Press): The Ministry of Refugees and Repatriation of Afghanistan has confirmed that approximately 100 Afghan migrants have returned from Iran.
 
 The Afghan Ministry said on its social media platform, X, that around 871 Afghan migrants had re-entered the country via the Islam Qala border. Whether these refugees were forcibly deported or returned to the country voluntarily is unclear.
 
 According to the ministry's report, these returnees have been referred to the International Organization for Migration's office for receiving food and non-food assistance.",2023-09-09 17:51:19,5214b7c54f5187666e509c4ee7acd575,0.024,0.976,0.0,-0.25,"[{'ent_text': 'KABUL', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Khaama Press', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'The Ministry of Refugees and Repatriation of Afghanistan', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'approximately 100', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Afghan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Iran', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'The Afghan Ministry', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'X', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'around 871', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Afghan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Islam Qala', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': ""the International Organization for Migration's"", 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
14,"Türkiye debunks disinformation on migrants, refugees",dailysabah.com,"As social media helps them disseminate fake news and disinformation, anti-migrant groups in Türkiye, home to millions of refugees from Syria and migrants from around the world, flourish. Combatting disinformation spread by those groups and often picked by far-right media outlets, the Turkish Presidency's Communications Directorate disproved claims smearing migrants and refugees.

In a weekly bulletin against disinformation, the Directorate debunked several reports portraying migrants and refugees as violent criminals.",2023-09-12 12:30:00,136dc46508d5a36c9899277bac70c0ed,0.135,0.832,0.033,-0.8442,"[{'ent_text': 'Türkiye', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'millions', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Syria', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': ""the Turkish Presidency's"", 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Communications Directorate', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'weekly', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Directorate', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
15,WHO collaborating centre in Italy continues to support refugee and migrant well-being,reliefweb.int,"The Italian National Institute for Health, Migration and Poverty (INMP) is now redesignated by WHO as a Collaborating Centre (CC) on Health and Migration Evidence and Capacity Building. To date, INMP has served as a CC for four years. It provides insights and offers context to support the design and implementation of policies that promote the health and well-being of refugees and migrants. The scope of its work surpasses national and European boundaries, sustaining Member States at a global level.",2023-09-13 22:03:06,76fbd62f37f4b004a3e5e0ec4bdfa4a1,0.039,0.9,0.062,0.25,"[{'ent_text': 'INMP', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'WHO', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'a Collaborating Centre (CC', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'INMP', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'four years', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'European', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}]"
16,Newborn found dead on refugee boat off Italy's island of Lampedusa,thenews.com.pk,"A migrant boat carrying refugees to Italy. — AFP
The Italian Coast Guard discovered a dead newborn baby on a refugee boat carrying people to Lampedusa as hundreds of the island's residents demonstrated against a recent spike in arrivals.
This year, about 126,000 migrants and refugees entered Italy, a number that was twice in 2022 around the same time.


More people have arrived in Lampedusa this week alone than the island's permanent population, prompting cries for assistance from local lawmakers, reported
 ANSA
.",2023-09-16 18:55:00,7733497ee247c9a72ec88523e3655c98,0.101,0.885,0.015,-0.8271,"[{'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'AFP', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'The Italian Coast Guard', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'hundreds', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'This year', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'about 126,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': '2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'this week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'ANSA', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
17,University of Limerick and Department of Health to collaborate on migrant and refugee health,limerickleader.ie,"AN INNOVATIVE new collaboration between University of Limerick (UL) and the Department of Health will involve refugees and migrants directly in the development of public health policy.
 
UL has launched a new public health partnership between the World Health Organisation (WHO) Collaborating Centre for Refugee and Migrant Health, based in UL's School of Medicine, and the Department of Health.
 
The Refugee and Migrant Health Partnership is funded by the Department of Health and is designed to involve refugees and migrants directly in the development of public health policy and will also fund bursaries for related teaching programmes and scholarships.",2023-10-07 07:00:08,08fcad97bf35571925e1ad3dcdd83bea,0.0,0.95,0.05,0.6289,"[{'ent_text': 'University of Limerick', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UL', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the Department of Health', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UL', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the World Health Organisation (WHO) Collaborating Centre for Refugee and Migrant Health', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UL', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'School of Medicine', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the Department of Health', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'The Refugee and Migrant Health Partnership', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the Department of Health', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
18,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,reuters.com,"Migrants wait at the port to be transferred to the mainland, on the Sicilian island of Lampedusa, Italy, September 15, 2023. REUTERS/Yara Nardi 
 Acquire Licensing Rights
GENEVA, Sept 15 (Reuters) - The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,7839ae499d4fa9da728d27d9bc4e65f0,0.021,0.919,0.06,0.5574,"[{'ent_text': 'Sicilian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'September 15, 2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Yara Nardi', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sept 15', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
19,Over Four Million Venezuelan Refugees and Migrants Struggle to Meet Basic Needs across the Americas,globaldiasporanews.com,"Photo credit: DiasporaEngager (www.DiasporaEngager.com). Geneva/Panama City – Despite efforts by host countries to regularize and integrate refugees and migrants from Venezuela, more than four million people still face difficulties accessing food, shelter, health care, education and formal employment in Latin America and the Caribbean.   The latest Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (RMNA) for 2023 […]


The post 
Over Four Million Venezuelan Refugees and Migrants Struggle to Meet Basic Needs across the Americas
 appeared first on 
Global Diaspora News
.",2023-09-12 16:06:38,ca1914d24ebacfe2685d87bb64aa1d2e,0.053,0.879,0.068,0.3182,"[{'ent_text': 'DiasporaEngager', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Geneva', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Panama City', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than four million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Refugee and Migrant Needs', 'ent_type': 'WORK_OF_ART'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Over Four Million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Americas', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Global Diaspora News', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
20,UN refugee agency : wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,marketscreener.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) - The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources. 
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy. 
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,61328b2f614826989031d579d7e1af51,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
21,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,yahoo.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) - The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,a3bac9d1e71c34b4e793e54478055e4d,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
22,Libya: Vote to Renew Measures to Combat Migrant Smuggling and Human Trafficking,reliefweb.int,"Today (29 September), following the closed consultations on the Democratic People's Republic of Korea (DPRK), the Security Council is expected to vote on a draft resolution renewing for one year the authorisation for member states, acting nationally or through regional organisations, to inspect and seize vessels on the high seas off the coast of 
Libya
 that they have reasonable grounds to suspect are being used for migrant smuggling or human trafficking from Libya. The Council initially established the authorisation through 
resolution 2240
 of 9 October 2015 and has since renewed it annually, most recently through 
resolution 2652
 of 29 September 2022.",2023-09-29 19:13:25,9fe9646f46dfcfe67de8d694605ac3af,0.05,0.927,0.023,-0.4404,"[{'ent_text': 'Today', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': '29 September', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': ""the Democratic People's Republic of Korea"", 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'DPRK', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the Security Council', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'one year', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Libya', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Libya', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Council', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': '2240', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '9 October 2015', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'annually', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'resolution 2652', 'ent_type': 'LAW'}, {'ent_text': '29 September 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
23,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,zawya.com,"The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.

Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.

Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:17:58,a8d6f0cfb94a8072c700cd85ad362be9,0.02,0.866,0.114,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
24,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,streetinsider.com,"Migrants wait at the port to be transferred to the mainland, on the Sicilian island of Lampedusa, Italy, September 15, 2023. REUTERS/Yara Nardi




GENEVA (Reuters) - The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.


Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.",2023-09-15 12:30:00,dd5c4233a851665ca4d15ae36ac4f804,0.022,0.914,0.064,0.5574,"[{'ent_text': 'Sicilian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'September 15, 2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Yara Nardi', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
25,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,wsau.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) – The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,5b82ff3f716ea0da146f8e1a87f46d8d,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
26,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,devdiscourse.com,"The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources. Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.
 
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:07:36,c0f1a6c7600801426b6c40537007bb79,0.02,0.866,0.114,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
27,Over 4 Million Venezuelan refugees and migrants struggle to meet basic needs across the Americas,indiaeducationdiary.in,"Despite efforts by host countries to regularize and integrate refugees and migrants from Venezuela, more than 4 million people still face difficulties accessing food, shelter, health care, education and formal employment in Latin America and the Caribbean.


The latest Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis (RMNA) for 2023 shows that many Venezuelan refugees and migrants in the region lack stable livelihood opportunities, making it difficult for them to effectively integrate and contribute to host communities.",2023-09-20 05:25:03,87bcc610248eb98fdce0cfb4f993ccbe,0.082,0.77,0.148,0.6908,"[{'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'more than 4 million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Refugee and Migrant Needs Analysis', 'ent_type': 'LAW'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuelan', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}]"
28,UN Refugee Agency: Wave of Migrants Must Be Moved off Island of Lampedusa,usnews.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) - The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.

Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.

Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:00,476c5daf1ceac26bc2b26664096b661c,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
29,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,thestar.com.my,"GENEVA (Reuters) - The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.

Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.

Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:13:00,5aa0a18110cdd1d69b35986e60505928,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
30,Where Do All the Migrants Go?,cis.org,"People from overseas do not simply settle in the United States, they decide to live in a particular place 
within
 America. How are those decisions made and who makes them is the subject of this post. We regard migrants as people who come here both temporarily and permanently, legally and illegally.


As I see it, there are three more or less natural forces at work here, and four others that relate to the government. They are:


Natural factors:


Choices made by migrants themselves, who are often related to earlier migrants; they tend to settle near their relatives and countrymen.",2023-09-15 16:30:22,2bd2137e45c6fc8a78eafb799a36d17f,0.0,0.912,0.088,0.8004,"[{'ent_text': 'the United States', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'America', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'three', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'four', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}]"
31,Loving Jesus in the migrant and refugee,thecompassnews.org,"Sept. 24 will mark the 109th World Day of Migrants and Refugees. It is an occasion that calls for a greater effort to care for these groups of vulnerable people in our society, and to raise awareness about the difficulties that migrants and refugees face. As Catholics, we are called to love our neighbor and, as Jesus teaches us in the parable of the Good Samaritan, our neighbor is anyone who is in need. Before …


 
 
Loving Jesus in the migrant and refugee
 Read More »


The post 
Loving Jesus in the migrant and refugee
 appeared first on 
The Compass
.",2023-09-26 13:55:00,26b43cb7a4d3ce10ce3a0f38935b2aa6,0.035,0.79,0.175,0.9552,"[{'ent_text': 'Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': '109th', 'ent_type': 'ORDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'World Day of Migrants and Refugees', 'ent_type': 'EVENT'}, {'ent_text': 'Catholics', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Jesus', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Jesus', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Loving Jesus', 'ent_type': 'WORK_OF_ART'}, {'ent_text': 'The Compass', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
32,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,whtc.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) – The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,9f5ccb542716867943640852a7644f94,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
33,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,todayonline.com,"GENEVA : The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.

Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.

Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,aa70eb5a7465b59c3f8a1c10253a82a3,0.02,0.869,0.112,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
34,World Day of Migrants and Refugees Sunday 24 September 2023.,sacbc.org.za,"109TH WORLD DAY OF MIGRANTS AND REFUGEES

'Free to choose whether to migrate or to stay'

'Let us keep the migrants, refugees, forcibly displaced people, asylum seekers and host

communities in our prayers. We also pray and acknowledge all who are making a

difference in the lives of migrants and displaced persons,' Liaison Bishop for Migrants and Refugees, Bishop Joseph Mary Kizito",2023-09-26 17:00:00,8369f3c6b6740481a7fef045dc64a6cb,0.0,0.915,0.085,0.6808,"[{'ent_text': 'WORLD DAY', 'ent_type': 'EVENT'}, {'ent_text': 'Joseph Mary Kizito', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}]"
35,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,wtvbam.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) – The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,10520b7add5c7ceaeacbca57c7719d66,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
36,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,i3investor.com,"GENEVA - The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.

Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.

Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 22:00:00,afda28f3495340449442a00930404d66,0.02,0.869,0.112,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
37,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,saltwire.com,"STORY CONTINUES BELOW THESE SALTWIRE VIDEOS
 
 
GENEVA (Reuters) - The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
 
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy. 
 
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:12:56,616f51099bdaa3c0305896841cf79ab4,0.018,0.878,0.104,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
38,Refugee-led language school helps migrants,cgtn.com,"02:57

""Rebuilding trust and reigniting global solidarity,"" will be on top of the agenda at this year's United Nations General Assembly.

One key global issue is the refugee crisis which has seen millions of people flee war-torn and poverty-stricken countries.

In Brazil, there are over 65,000 registered refugees, a number that grows steadily every year, but one initiative is providing refugees and vulnerable migrants an opportunity to start a new life by using their native languages.",2023-09-14 21:37:54,510f79261fdd3a18147d8a33c9bd39b0,0.058,0.802,0.14,0.6124,"[{'ent_text': 'year', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations General Assembly', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'One', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'millions', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Brazil', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': '65,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'one', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}]"
39,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,kelo.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) – The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,7baede7a792009d1eabc6a05b367e5ed,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
40,Mental Health of Migrants and Refugees,southernafrican.news,"Migration is a phenomenon as old as humanity itself. 
People
 have been moving from one place to another in search of better opportunities, safety, and a brighter future. However, this journey isn't always smooth, and the mental health of migrants and refugees often hangs in the balance. In this exploration, we will delve into the intricacies of their experiences, the mental challenges they face, and the various factors contributing to their mental well-being.





A migrant is an individual who moves from one place to another, either within a country or internationally.",2023-09-15 07:30:20,4bbb0831bcbf6370ed10212b1b0b821f,0.0,0.856,0.144,0.9067,"[{'ent_text': 'one', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}]"
41,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,whbl.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) – The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,29652d2804087499220c99db46c3bceb,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
42,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,kdal610.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) – The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,a4ba2f5fbd90d703d81dc9cd6670b333,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
43,"World Day of Migrants and Refugees 2023: History, Dates, Activities, and FAQs",newsd.in,"World Day of Migrants and Refugees 2023: World Day of Migrants and Refugees is observed annually on September 26 or the last Sunday of September. It is a day designated annually by the United Nations to commemorate and honor people who have been compelled to flee their homes, people who have escaped conflict, encountered adversity, and, against all odds, forged their way to find greener pastures in faraway places.

This day has been designated to honor the fortitude and bravery of these individuals and to deepen our comprehension of their plight and the difficult decisions many immigrants have had to make.",2023-09-26 07:30:31,af64781d106f90eee2757197c62fb693,0.067,0.814,0.119,0.7184,"[{'ent_text': 'World Day of Migrants and Refugees 2023', 'ent_type': 'EVENT'}, {'ent_text': 'World Day of Migrants and', 'ent_type': 'EVENT'}, {'ent_text': 'September 26', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'the last Sunday of September', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'a day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
44,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,wdez.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) – The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,252853b11fd30b00e32dbb0584aa4808,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
45,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,wkzo.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) – The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,e8c185556a47c7eb51d8e2d333a08949,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
46,Churches celebrate World Day of Migrants and Refugees,thetablet.co.uk,"International Mass in Westminster Cathedral with the Ethnic Communities in London for World Day of Migrants and Refugees



Mazur/cbcew.org.uk








Westminster cathedral held an international Mass last Sunday for the World Day of Migrants and Refugees. Nottingham was among the dioceses displaying on websites resources for the day from the Jesuit Refugee Service UK. These included bidding prayers during Mass and information for parish newsletters.


Cafod offered a special prayer, picking up on the day's message from Pope Francis, 'Free to choose whether to migrate or to stay'.",2023-09-26 12:15:00,d1274c0ea460d70d65dec9217905beb4,0.0,0.934,0.066,0.7184,"[{'ent_text': 'Westminster Cathedral', 'ent_type': 'FAC'}, {'ent_text': 'London', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'World Day of Migrants and Refugees', 'ent_type': 'EVENT'}, {'ent_text': 'Westminster', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'last Sunday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'the World Day of Migrants and Refugees', 'ent_type': 'EVENT'}, {'ent_text': 'Nottingham', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'the Jesuit Refugee Service', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Cafod', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Francis', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}]"
47,"Erdoğan vows concurrent fight against illegal migration, racism",dailysabah.com,"As racist messages perpetrated by far-right groups against 
refugees and migrants
 flood social media, President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan reiterated Türkiye's stance on the issue. He stressed that they would not tolerate illegal migration but would also stand against racist behavior and attacks targeting migrants, as well as millions of refugees who fled the war in neighboring Syria.
 
Erdoğan was addressing prospective district governors at an event in the capital Ankara on Thursday as he highlighted his government's stand on the issue.",2023-09-14 12:46:00,fbcb5c2cd791bff0410f9da6c773ed19,0.194,0.759,0.047,-0.9459,"[{'ent_text': 'Recep Tayyip Erdoğan', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Türkiye', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'millions', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Syria', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Erdoğan', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Ankara', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
48,"186,000 migrants, refugees have arrived in southern Europe in 2023, UN says",foxnews.com,"According to the United Nations, about 186,000 migrants or refugees arrived in Southern Europe in 2023 so far.
The majority of Southern Europe's refugees and migrants departed from Tunisia or Libya, but about 2,500 people who attempted to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or remain missing. 
2022 reported fewer people who died or went missing while trying to reach Southern Europe with a count of 1,680.
The U.N. refugee agency said Thursday that some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in Southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy.",2023-09-29 11:32:37,c73af646da715d9939b5f16e044bf592,0.156,0.815,0.029,-0.9468,"[{'ent_text': 'the United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'about 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Southern Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': ""Southern Europe's"", 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Libya', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'about 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '2022', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Southern Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Southern Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'this year', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
49,UN refugee agency: wave of migrants must be moved off island of Lampedusa,wincountry.com,"GENEVA (Reuters) – The United Nations refugee agency on Friday said it was imperative that the thousands of migrants who have arrived in recent days on the Italian island of Lampedusa be relocated because of its limited resources.
Around 7,000 migrants arrived on the shore of the small island in a two-day period, prompting pleas for help from Italy.
Authorities have organised some transfers to the larger island of Sicily to ease the situation, something the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) expects will continue in the coming days.",2023-09-15 12:10:04,a254d35b1b3c38f3f734f82ca4efee9f,0.019,0.87,0.111,0.836,"[{'ent_text': 'GENEVA', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'United Nations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'recent days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Around 7,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'two-day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Sicily', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the coming days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
50,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says",go.com,"The U.N. refugee agency says some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy
September 28, 2023, 11:07 PM
UNITED NATIONS -- 
The U.N. refugee agency said Thursday that some 186,000 migrants and 
refugees
 arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in 
Italy
.
Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.",2023-09-29 03:07:20,84260c041853d0fbf47686d08f50ec45,0.103,0.832,0.064,-0.6875,"[{'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'September 28, 2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': '11:07 PM', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'UNITED NATIONS', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'U.', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
51,Bishops in South Africa Unveil 'liturgy kit' To Pray for Migrants and Refugees,aciafrica.org,"The 
109th World Day for Migrants and Refugees
 that was celebrated on Sunday, September 24, on the theme, 'Free to choose whether to migrate or to stay.'
 
In his statement, Bishop Kizito said that like any other human beings, migrants and refugees have families and have permission to decide whether to stay or to migrate.
 
He said, 'Host countries should not make it difficult for families to join their members who are already burdened with the challenges of migration. This imposes a biblical and moral obligation on us all to be an inclusive society.",2023-09-29 15:35:00,a20b548db8c257ca5a1b6f1ec0cdd873,0.04,0.817,0.143,0.8723,"[{'ent_text': '109th', 'ent_type': 'ORDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'World Day', 'ent_type': 'EVENT'}, {'ent_text': 'Sunday, September 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Kizito', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}]"
52,"UN reveals over 2,500 now dead or missing as 186,000 cross Mediterranean in 2023",headtopics.com,"There has been nearly a 50 increase in refugee deaths and dissapearances while making the risky ocean crossing compared to the same period in 2022. Thousands hope to reach Europe from Tunisia, which has replaced Libya as the main base of operations for migrant smuggling operations in the Mediterranean (Cecilia Fabiano/LaPresse /AP) The UN refugee agency has revealed the number of refugees and...
Thousands hope to reach Europe from Tunisia, which has replaced Libya as the main base of operations for migrant smuggling operations in the Mediterranean (Cecilia Fabiano/LaPresse /AP) The UN refugee agency has revealed the number of refugees and migrants seeking safety in Europe has increased by 83% for 2023.",2023-09-29 04:12:00,d2c015ee83af3ee0abd8d25d0d667501,0.064,0.795,0.141,0.7003,"[{'ent_text': '50', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Libya', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Cecilia Fabiano', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'UN', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Thousands', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Libya', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Cecilia Fabiano', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'UN', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '83%', 'ent_type': 'PERCENT'}, {'ent_text': '2023', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
53,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says",seattlepi.com,"The U.N. refugee agency says some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy. Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, told the U.N. Security Council. The UNHCR estimates that over 102,000 refugees and migrants from Tunisia and over 45,000 from Libya tried to cross the central Mediterranean to Europe between January and August.",2023-09-29 03:07:21,5cc9350608e77911d0307f9d40886675,0.102,0.844,0.054,-0.7783,"[{'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'this year', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. Security Council', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'UNHCR', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'over 102,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 45,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Libya', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'between January and August', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
54,German Government Under Pressure As Refugee Numbers Surge,haberler.com,"The German government has come under mounting pressure to tackle migration as the number of irregular migrants entering the country surged in recent months.

Germany's main opposition party, the conservative CDU/CSU alliance, on Sunday renewed its call for a 200,000 ceiling on the number of refugees the country accepts annually.

Christian Social Union's (CSU) chairman and Bavarian premier Markus Soder said the country does not have the capacity to integrate more than 200,000 refugees annually.

""We are for helping refugees, but we are against uncontrolled immigration to Germany,"" Soder told public broadcaster ARD on Sunday night.",2023-09-25 11:11:00,aa913175ba660e936c8914ebf649def0,0.041,0.886,0.074,0.0772,"[{'ent_text': 'German', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'recent months', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Germany', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'CDU/CSU', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Sunday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': '200,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'annually', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': ""Christian Social Union's"", 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'CSU', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Bavarian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Markus Soder', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'more than 200,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'annually', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Germany', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Soder', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'ARD', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Sunday night', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}]"
55,Mexico is on the verge of breaking asylum records due to massive arrival of Cubans,babalublog.com,"From our Bureau of Weaponized Migrations 
with some assistance from our
 Bureau of Black Holes That Swallow Migrants
 
A Cuban migrant currently stuck in Mexico said this past week that staying in the Mexican city of Tapachula was like 'entering a black hole that swallows migrants.' See story below.
 
An unstoppable wave of Cubans keep entering Mexico, hoping to be granted asylum in the U.S. Many of these Cubans get to Mexico by flying to Nicaragua. Others get there by trekking much longer distances from Venezuela or Colombia, crossing the treacherous Darien Gap in Panama.",2023-09-17 22:00:00,f242e1cbd38b01671f81390ea4aff26a,0.038,0.89,0.072,0.5423,"[{'ent_text': 'Bureau of Weaponized Migrations', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'our\n Bureau of Black Holes That Swallow', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Cuban', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Mexico', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'this past week', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Mexican', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Tapachula', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Cubans', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Mexico', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'U.S.', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Cubans', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Mexico', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Nicaragua', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Venezuela', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Colombia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Darien Gap', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Panama', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
56,"More refugees to come from Latin America, Caribbean under Biden's new 125,000 refugee cap",headtopics.com,"As the number of migrants coming to the U.S.'s southern border is climbing, the Biden administration aims to admit more refugees from Latin America and the Caribbean over the next year The White House Friday released the targets for how many refugees it aims to admit over the next fiscal year starting October 1 and from what regions of the world.
But in a significant shift, the administration said it aims to admit 35,000 to 50,000 refugees from Latin America and the Caribbean compared to this year's goal of 15,000.",2023-09-29 13:21:00,f7a74ba8cf881cde794754d9f858e7b0,0.0,0.911,0.089,0.6542,"[{'ent_text': 'U.S.', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Biden', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'the next year', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'The White House', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'the next fiscal year starting October 1', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': '35,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': '50,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Latin America', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Caribbean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'year', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': '15,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}]"
57,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says",chron.com,"UNITED NATIONS (AP) — The U.N. refugee agency said Thursday that some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy.

Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, told the U.",2023-09-29 03:07:21,fd3eff7d9e2dbfecf72096566276f4c5,0.126,0.796,0.078,-0.6875,"[{'ent_text': 'UNITED NATIONS', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'U.', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
58,186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far ...,washingtonpost.com,"Share Comment on this story Comment

UNITED NATIONS — The U.N. refugee agency said Thursday that some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy. Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, told the U.",2023-09-29 03:07:52,82ce62c4a6fd38562d2434f22dd712e7,0.118,0.787,0.094,-0.5372,"[{'ent_text': 'UNITED NATIONS', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'U.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
59,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says",dailymail.co.uk,"UNITED NATIONS (AP) - The U.N. refugee agency said Thursday that some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy.

Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, told the U.",2023-09-29 03:10:05,b07d083987cf6419f5b253afcfd2d686,0.126,0.796,0.078,-0.6875,"[{'ent_text': 'UNITED NATIONS', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'U.', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
60,West can protect real asylum seekers but need to send home migrant cheats,express.co.uk,"Channel chaos...another small boat heading to Dover 
(Image: Getty)
The vast majority of young men crossing the English Channel are not refugees but economic migrants jumping the queue of legal migration – everyone can see that except the lefty activists defending them – and Home Secretary Suella Braverman was right to point out that fact in a speech in Washington DC yesterday. They are not fleeing persecution and should not get refugee status.
With as many as 780 million people eligible to claim asylum under current UN rules, Suella rightly says their Refugee Convention is far too lax in its definition of a refugee, allowing millions of economic migrants to push through our frontiers, denying other legal immigrants their turn and making millions for people-trafficking gangsters.",2023-09-26 21:01:00,ab7e563becb92492d2c4e033844e4a5b,0.024,0.949,0.027,-0.1531,"[{'ent_text': 'Dover', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Getty', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the English Channel', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Home', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Suella Braverman', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Washington DC', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'yesterday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'as many as 780 million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'UN', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Suella', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Refugee Convention', 'ent_type': 'LAW'}, {'ent_text': 'millions', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'millions', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}]"
61,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says",pantheonsite.io,"UNITED NATIONS (AP) — The U.N. refugee agency says some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy. Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, told the U.N. Security Council.",2023-09-29 03:07:21,064763e643c4900ccbdf561dc9e1f806,0.124,0.775,0.101,-0.5052,"[{'ent_text': 'UNITED NATIONS', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'this year', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. Security Council', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
62,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says",houstonchronicle.com,"UNITED NATIONS (AP) — The U.N. refugee agency said Thursday that some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy.

Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, told the U.",2023-09-29 03:07:21,d8af87f0fc78f57fa15060520a85e761,0.126,0.796,0.078,-0.6875,"[{'ent_text': 'UNITED NATIONS', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'U.', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
63,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says",wral.com,"UNITED NATIONS (AP) — The U.N. refugee agency said Thursday that some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy.
Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, told the U.",2023-09-29 03:08:13,218dc71b0d77caa09946aab568a69545,0.126,0.796,0.078,-0.6875,"[{'ent_text': 'UNITED NATIONS', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'U.', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
64,"Pakistan's Behaviour Against Afghan Refugees is Unacceptable, Says Taliban",news18.com,"A day after Pakistan announced a major crackdown on illegal migrants in the country, the Taliban on Wednesday denounced the decision to expel refugees as unacceptable. Taking to social media platform X, a Taliban spokesperson said as long as the refugees don't leave the country voluntarily, Pakistan should 'tolerate them.'
On Tuesday, Pakistan's interim government said it would expel all refugees, including an estimated 1.7 million from Afghanistan. Islamabad said the crackdown, starting next month, was not aimed at anyone in particular and would apply to all nationalities.",2023-10-04 09:54:44,1acd909aee5045220cc5cc14656d0a3c,0.131,0.857,0.012,-0.9103,"[{'ent_text': 'A day', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Pakistan', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Taliban', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Wednesday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'X', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Taliban', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Pakistan', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Tuesday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Pakistan', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'an estimated 1.7 million', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Afghanistan', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Islamabad', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'next month', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}]"
65,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says",krdo.com,"UNITED NATIONS (AP) — The U.N. refugee agency says some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy. Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, told the U.N. Security Council.",2023-09-29 03:07:21,3d7c94d3bcc2b7e948848f431d7b1d9b,0.124,0.775,0.101,-0.5052,"[{'ent_text': 'UNITED NATIONS', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'this year', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. Security Council', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
66,Germany says it will keep taking in migrants from Italy after all,headtopics.com,"FRANKFURT (Reuters) - Germany has decided to keep taking in migrants and refugees arriving in Italy, the interior minister said late on Friday, two ... FRANKFURT (Reuters) - Germany has decided to keep taking in migrants and refugees arriving in Italy, the interior minister said late on Friday, two days after it announced the suspension of a STORY CONTINUES BELOW THESE SALTWIRE VIDEOS Lee's...
FRANKFURT (Reuters) - Germany has decided to keep taking in migrants and refugees arriving in Italy, the interior minister said late on Friday, two days after it announced the suspension of a STORY CONTINUES BELOW THESE SALTWIRE VIDEOS
Lee's impacts to be felt as the storm tracks into Atlantic Canada this weekend | SaltWire Watch on FRANKFURT (Reuters) - Germany has decided to keep taking in migrants and refugees arriving in Italy, the interior minister said late on Friday, two days after it announced the suspension of a voluntary agreement with Rome to receive new arrivals.",2023-09-16 04:03:00,25bd03e674898628e651070cc746c635,0.0,0.98,0.02,0.4939,"[{'ent_text': 'FRANKFURT', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Germany', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'two', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'FRANKFURT', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Germany', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'late on', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'two days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lee', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'FRANKFURT', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Germany', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'late on', 'ent_type': 'TIME'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'two days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Lee', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Atlantic Canada', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'this weekend', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'FRANKFURT', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Reuters', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Germany', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'two days', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Rome', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
67,"Migrants and refugees Mass in Canada celebrates universality, vibrancy of the Church",catholicnewsagency.com,"In his homily, Father Richard Zanotti said it's essential that migrants and refugees don't get blamed for seeking a life of dignity.
 
'The universality of the Church is made visible by all of you gathered for this Eucharist, many cultures around one table to celebrate God's love for us all,' said the Scalabrinian pastor of St. Ann's, where he works with migrant workers in the Fraser Valley.
 
The Church teaches us that we all have a right to a life of dignity, replete with basic human needs like food, shelter, medical attention, and dignified work, he said.",2023-10-07 11:00:00,fd5cfb4fe3fb0add349cb18d33311f05,0.0,0.807,0.193,0.9664,"[{'ent_text': 'Richard Zanotti', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Church', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'one', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Scalabrinian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': ""St. Ann's"", 'ent_type': 'FAC'}, {'ent_text': 'the Fraser Valley', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Church', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
68,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says",apnews.com,"UNITED NATIONS (AP) — The U.N. refugee agency said Thursday that some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy.

Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, told the U.",2023-09-29 03:07:21,59e79211bc626d2804ad49867eea1acc,0.126,0.796,0.078,-0.6875,"[{'ent_text': 'UNITED NATIONS', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'U.', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
69,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says – KION546",pantheonsite.io,"UNITED NATIONS (AP) — The U.N. refugee agency says some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy. Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, told the U.N. Security Council.",2023-09-29 03:07:21,a938256ddcf63ee9fbf59b7f2d54232f,0.124,0.775,0.101,-0.5052,"[{'ent_text': 'UNITED NATIONS', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'this year', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. Security Council', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}]"
70,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says",seattletimes.com,"UNITED NATIONS (AP) — The U.N. refugee agency said Thursday that some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy.

Between January and Sept. 24, over 2,500 people seeking to cross the Mediterranean were found dead or are still missing, a significant increase from the 1,680 people who died or were missing during the same period in 2022, Ruven Menikdiwela, director of the New York office of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, told the U.",2023-09-29 03:08:06,139a9793835808e684f82acd565974b3,0.126,0.796,0.078,-0.6875,"[{'ent_text': 'UNITED NATIONS', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'U.N.', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Thursday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'some 186,000', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Europe', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italy', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'Between January and Sept. 24', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'over 2,500', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': '1,680', 'ent_type': 'CARDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'the same period in 2022', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'Ruven Menikdiwela', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'New York', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'U.', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}]"
71,Italy's Meloni Invites EU Commission Head To Lampedusa Amid Migration Crisis,haberler.com,"Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni said Friday she invited EU Commission President Ursula von der Leyen to see first-hand the seriousness of the situation at Lampedusa, the tiny Italian Mediterranean island overwhelmed with migrants.

Meloni said she is hopeful von der Leyen will join her and will accelerate the deployment of the EU resources promised to Tunisia in exchange for blocking migrants' departures from that country.

""President von der Leyen has always been very collaborative. I don't doubt she will be so this time too,"" Meloni said in a video message circulated by her office.",2023-09-16 03:00:00,0f4db45c9c4c45998e86feabd4ecbb6e,0.037,0.852,0.111,0.7587,"[{'ent_text': 'Giorgia Meloni', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Friday', 'ent_type': 'DATE'}, {'ent_text': 'EU Commission', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Ursula von der Leyen', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'first', 'ent_type': 'ORDINAL'}, {'ent_text': 'Lampedusa', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Italian', 'ent_type': 'NORP'}, {'ent_text': 'Mediterranean', 'ent_type': 'LOC'}, {'ent_text': 'Meloni', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'von der Leyen', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'EU', 'ent_type': 'ORG'}, {'ent_text': 'Tunisia', 'ent_type': 'GPE'}, {'ent_text': 'von der Leyen', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}, {'ent_text': 'Meloni', 'ent_type': 'PERSON'}]"
72,"186.000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, most in Italy, UN says",startribune.com,"UNITED NATIONS — The U.N. refugee agency said Thursday that some 186,000 migrants and refugees arrived in southern Europe so far this year, the vast majority in Italy.
